(Respiration)
春野さん　早く
Haruno-san, quick!
The others will come for
us if we can make it out.
直ぐにギルドの異能力者が来ますわ
Naomi-chan, are you sure the
detectives will come help us?
ねえ　ナオミちゃん
探偵社の方々は扶けに来てくれるかしら
兄様がいますもの
We have my brother.
必ず扶けに来てくれますわ
I'm certain he'll come.
いいロッジだ　土地も耕せばいい果樹園になるよ
This is a great lodge.
We can make a nice orchard
here, once we till the land.
捕獲の方法は？
How do we capture them?
君の能力だと　彼女達の首がもげる
You'd just rip their heads
off, with your ability.
Let's go with my grapes.
僕の「葡萄」でいこう
There you are.
そこか
なに
What was that?
何かが車体に…
Something's got the car.
ドアが開きません
I can't open the door.
木の根？
Tree roots?
We're going to get crushed!
このままじゃ押し潰されますわ
申し訳ないね　お嬢様方
Sorry about that, ladies.
君達　葡萄をどうやって育てるか知ってる
Do you know how grapes are made?
葡萄の枝は他の植物と活着する力が強い
Grape vines are adept at attaching to
other plants, so their scions are grafted.
だから接ぎ木して育てるんだ
こんな風に
Like this.
By merging my grape vine
with the other plants,
僕の葡萄の樹と他の植物をこうして融合していけば
この土地一帯の植物を体の延長として使える
I can use all the plants around
here as an extension of my body.
植物と感覚を共有しているから　地中の根で振動をキャッチして
And since I'm sharing my
senses with all the plants,
逃げる誰かさんを見つけるのも簡単ってわけ
it's easy for me to find you running off.
そう怖い顔しないでよ　少し頼みがあるだけさ
Don't look so upset.
I just need you to do me a favor.
悪党にとっての「頼み」は「利用して奪い使い捨てる」の類義ですわ
When a villain asks for a "favor,"
it's something along the lines of
"Take advantage, exploit, and discard."
The Guild isn't an evil organization.
ギルドは悪の組織じゃないよ
勿論僕も
Of course...
故郷に君くらいの齢の妹がいるんだ
I have a sister back
home who's about your age.
大家族でね　夕食は戦争さ
It's a huge family.
The dinner table is a warzone.
My sister loves pie.
妹はパイが好物で　いつも僕の分まで食べる
She'd always take my share.
でも可愛くてつい許しちゃうんだな
But she's so cute, I let
her get away with it.
だったら私達を逃して
Then let us go.
勘違いさせたなら謝るよ
Sorry if I gave you the wrong impression.
ギルドの仕事は過酷な分　払いがいいんだ
The Guild's work is treacherous,
but the pay is good.
If I were to get fired,
my family would starve.
もしクビにでもなれば　故郷の家族が飢える
もうやめて…
Please, stop.
妹の為なら　君達がどうなろうと知ったことじゃない
I don't care what happens to
you, if it's for my sister.
Snow? In this season?
こんな季節に雪が？
Naomi, run!
ナオミ　逃げるんだ
兄様
Brother!
五分後　麓の線路を旅客列車が通る
A passenger train is passing
by in five minutes.
一分だけ止まってくれるよう話をつけてある
I'll convince them to wait
for just one minute.
それに飛び乗れ
Jump on.
さあ走れ　振り返るな
Now, run!
Don't look back!
こうなる気はしてたよ
I thought this might happen.
信頼できない情報源だったからね
My sources weren't very reliable.
先刻見せた奴の異能力
Given his ability as I saw it earlier,
一度樹木と繋がれば　麓の樹木を操って列車を停止できるだろう
as soon as he connects with the woods,
he'll be able to manipulate the roots at
the base of the hill and stop the train.
事務員達が逃げおおせるまでの五分間　奴に一度も樹木に触れさせてはならん
I can't let him touch any trees
for five minutes so our staff can get away.
Kunikida-san!
国木田さん
今こう思ったね
You just thought, "I'll win if I don't let
him touch any trees while the girls run away."
「彼女達が逃げきるまで　僕に樹木を触らせなければ勝ちだ」って
Simplify your understanding
of the battlefield too much,
戦況を簡略化しすぎると　行動が単調になる
and your behavior becomes easy to read.
なるほど　後で手帳に書き控えよう
Indeed.
I'll have to write that
down in my notebook later.
By the way, did you just have this thought?
ところで貴様は先刻こう思わなかったか
「拳銃を叩き落とせば　もう攻撃手段はない」と
"Slap away his pistol, and he'll
have no means of attacking me."
「独歩吟客」
Doppo Poet!
Simplify your understanding
of the battlefield too much,
戦況を簡略化しすぎると行動が単調になるぞ
and your behavior becomes easy to read.
後でメモしておけ
Write that down later.
A secret organization from the
superpower abducting people abroad, I see.
超大国の秘密組織が異国で誘拐業とはな
耳が痛いね
That hurts to hear.
でも団長が云ってたよ
My boss told me, though, that the Guild
isn't an organization that does good.
ギルドはいいことをする組織ではない
すべきことをする組織だってね
It's an organization that
does what needs to be done.
Kunikida-san, behind you!
国木田さん　後ろ
What?!
なに
Do his abilities make him immune to bullets?
銃の効かぬ異能力者か
遅いよ　ラヴクラフト
You're late, Lovecraft.
What were you doing?
何してたの
Sleeping.
寝てた
こらこら
Oh, you.
すまん
Sorry.
Tanizaki! Use your Light Snow to hide!
谷崎　「細雪」で姿を…
What is this ability?
なんだこの力は
It's way too powerful a gift.
異能力にしても異形すぎる
こいつらは殺すのか
Do we kill them?
I don't know.
どうだろう
取り敢えず女の子達を捕まえてから　指示を仰ごう
Let's catch the girls first,
and then ask for orders.
あれですわ
There it is.
春野さん
Haruno-san!
列車が…
The train.
よーし
All right, job's done.
業務終了
Let's pull out before the
local police arrive.
地元警察が来る前に撤収だ
There's no point hiding
myself with Light Snow now.
これじゃ「細雪」で姿を消しても意味がない
何か方法は…
What can I do?
I'm borrowing your sister.
妹さん　借りてくよ
ナオミをどうする気だ
What are you doing with Naomi?
担当じゃないから何とも
I'm not assigned to her, so I don't know.
Confine her... Torture her, I guess.
まあ　監禁か拷問か
Don't think you can get away with this!
そんなことが許されると思ってるのか
これが仕事だよ
This is work.
You moralists would never understand.
君達みたいな道徳家には理解できないかな
道徳？
Morals?
A truck.
貨物車？
Things could get nasty if they saw this.
この状況を見られると厄介だな
Sure, the Agency has a sense of morals.
確かに探偵社には道徳観がある
But Naomi is different to me.
でもボクにとってナオミは違うんだ
道徳観とか悪　モラルやエゴ
Justice, morals, ego...
She's so much more to me than any of
those things that I can't compare them.
そういうものより次元が上で較べられない
あの貨物車　こっちに気づいてないのか
Hasn't that truck noticed us?
まさか…
No.
Do we look like part of
the road to the driver?!
こちらが道に見えているのか
For Naomi, I'd gladly burn the world.
それがナオミの為なら　ボクは喜んで世界を焼く
動きが止まった
They stopped moving.
春野さん
Haruno-san!
驚いた
That was unexpected.
Where'd they go?
連中は
I don't sense their presence.
気配がない
It seems they hid themselves and escaped.
姿を消して　逃げたようだ
追おう
動くな
Freeze!
本部　通報の誘拐犯らしき二人組を発見しました
HQ, we've found the suspects
in the reported abductions.
事前に通報してあったってわけだね
So they reported us ahead of time.
ナオミさん達が乗ったっていう列車　遅いですね
That train is late, the one
they're supposed to be on.
ポートマフィアの森さんは合理化の権化でね
Mori-san from the Port Mafia is the human
manifestation of streamlining.
数式の如き冷徹さで戦況を支配する
He controls the situation with
cold, mathematical detachment.
だから刺客から逃れて気が緩む今を狙って
You can count on him to take advantage of
the fact we're letting our guard down.
必ず何か仕掛けてくるよ
We'll be safe for a while now.
これで当面は安全ですわ
そうね
Uh-huh.
ごめんなさい
Sorry.
ごめんなさい？
Sorry?
こちらこそごめんなさい
I'm sorry, too.
Are you hurt?
お怪我は
敦君
Atsushi-kun.
はい？
Yes?
避けられない案件が生じた
I have an unavoidable item on my agenda.
どうしました
What is it?
I'm going to the bathroom.
トイレに行ってくる
漏る　漏る漏る漏る…
I'm not going to make it!
ここなら人目もない　出てきたら
There's no one watching us here.
You ought to come out.
やあ　銀ちゃんか
Hey, Gin-chan.
背　伸びたね
You've grown taller.
So you knew we were watching you.
監視はお見通しということですか
I was the one who created the Port Mafia's
surveillance techniques, after all.
ポートマフィアの監視術を創始したのは私だからね
So, what do you want from me?
で　用件は
Don't you think this gun
tells you what we want?
この銃が用件だとは思いませんか
思わないね
I don't.
暗殺部隊にしては人選が半端だ
For a group of assassins,
you've recruited some lousy members.
Gin-chan, would you please put
this away? It's dangerous.
銀ちゃん　危ないからこれ下げてくれる
確かに用件は別です
You're right, that's not why we're here.
I have a message from the boss.
首領より伝言を預かってきました
From Mori-san, huh?
へえ　森さんから？
何かな
I wonder what it is.
伝言はこうです
The message is this:
太宰君
Dazai-kun, are you interested in coming
back to the Port Mafia executives?
ポートマフィアの幹部に戻る気はないかね
いや　実にお目出度いお誘いだ
Ah, what a pleasant invitation.
I've looked at your records.
貴方の記録を見ました
Your blood is mafia black.
貴方の血はマフィアの黒です　この国の誰よりも
More so than anyone in this nation.
People change.
人は変わるものだ
I mean, Gin-chan over there was
a dainty little girl, this tall.
現にそこの銀ちゃんだって
昔はこーんなに小さくて可憐な少女だったのだよ
話をすり替えないでください
Don't change the subject.
And she has
a sweet voice.
お…女？
G-Girl?
春野さん　ナオミさん
Haruno-san.
Naomi-san.
You were safe.
ご無事でしたか
Yes.
ええ
I never thought they'd come
after the staff, though.
でもまさか事務員が狙われるなんて
もう大丈夫です　僕達が避難拠点まで護衛しますから
You're safe now.
We'll escort you to the extraction point.
しかし　腑に落ちないね
Something doesn't add up, though.
森さんがこんな茶番に人員を割くとは
Why would Mori-san set people
aside for this charade?
In order to protect you.
貴方を守る為です
To protect me?
守る為？
The boss has set Q free.
首領はＱを座敷牢から解き放ちました
Oh yeah, let me introduce someone to you.
そうだ　紹介しますわ
We got acquainted on the train.
列車内で知り合ったのですけど
Whoa.
What the?
なんだ　カミソリをテープで腕に巻きつけている
There are razors taped
The slightest bump would hurt him.
あれじゃ　軽くぶつかっただけで　カミソリが腕を傷つける
Let's play.
さあ　遊ぼう
莫迦な
Impossible.
何を解き放ったかわかっているのか
Do you have any idea what he's unleashed?
Ｑは敵も味方も凡て滅ぼす歩く厄災だ
Q is a walking catastrophe.
He'll doom everyone, friend or foe.
闘争を制する為ならば　ポートマフィアは手段を選びません
The Port Mafia doesn't choose its
means to reach its ends.
Why do you think Q was
imprisoned in the first place?
何故Ｑが座敷牢に封印されたと思う
It was because he has the most abhorrent
ability of them all. Mind control.
異能力の中でも尤も忌み嫌われる精神操作の異能力者だからだよ
You better do something,
or he's going to die.
何とかしなきゃ死んじゃうよ
敵の異能力攻撃
The enemy's gift...
I have to protect them.
僕がみんなを守らないと
貴様には何も守れん
You can't protect anyone.
What do you think you can protect?
貴様如きが何を守れる
No.
違う　もう昔の僕じゃない
I'm not the same person I was before.
僕には力がある
I have power.
すみません　春野さん
I'm sorry, Haruno-san.
Q's curse attacks the minds of
his victims with hallucinations.
Ｑの詛いが発動した者は　幻覚に精神を冒され　周囲を無差別に襲う
They begin to attack the people
around them indiscriminately.
詛いを発動させる契機は
The curse is triggered by the destruction
of the doll at the root of the curse.
詛いの根源たる人形が破壊されることだ
But only a receiver is
cursed when that happens.
ただし人形が破壊された時　詛いを受けるのは受信者のみ
受信者になる条件はＱを傷つけること
In order to become a receiver,
one must hurt Q.
受信者の体には誰かに掴まれたような痣が浮かび上がるから　判別は容易だ
Receivers show a bruise that looks as
though they were grabbed by someone,
which makes them easy to distinguish.
ここに来た時　私を守る為と云ったね
You mentioned that you
came here to protect me.
Damn!
しまった
Stop, Atsushi-kun!
やめるんだ　敦君　よく見ろ
Look carefully!
Atsushi-san...
敦さん　やめて
Stop.
そんな…
No...
最初から僕だけが操られていたのか
I was the only one being
manipulated this whole time?
僕はただみんなを守ろうとして…
I was only trying to protect them.
It's all your fault.
凡て貴様の所為だ
力に呑まれ　他者を害するその本質は一生変わらぬ
It's in your nature to be swept up
by power and hurt others.
That will never change.
No!
違う　僕は変わりたくて
It's your fault.
I want to change.
Be gone from this world.
ただみんなを守ろうと
I just want to protect people.
やめろー
Stop!
これでわかったか　己が何者か
Now do you understand who you are?
消えろ　異能力「人間失格」
Be gone.
Ability: No Longer Human.
太宰さんの新しいお友達って　壊れやすいんだね
Your new friends are so fragile, Dazai-san.
It's okay, though.
でもいいんだ　太宰さんを壊す楽しみが残っているもの
I still look forward to breaking you.
Q
Yumeno Kyusaku
Ability:
Dogra Magra
In return for making me suffer, I'm
going to hurt you and break you lots.
僕を閉じ込めたお礼に
いっぱい苦しめて壊してあげるね
次は封印などしない　心臓を刳り貫く
I won't capture you next time.
I'll rip your heart out.
また遊ぼうね　太宰さん
Let's play again, Dazai-san.
Let's go, Atsushi-kun.
行くよ　敦君　立つんだ
Get up.
I'm no good!
僕は駄目だ
僕はいちゃいけなかったんだ
I shouldn't have existed.
Atsushi-kun.
敦君
Listen to me, Atsushi-kun.
聞きたまえ　敦君
I'll give you some advice for
once, like a proper senpai.
たまには先輩らしい助言でもしよう
Stop pitying yourself.
自分を憐れむな
自分を憐れめば　人生は終わりなき悪夢だよ
Pity yourself, and life becomes
an endless nightmare.
Now, then...
却説　私達も手段を選んでいる場合ではなくなった
We don't have the luxury of choosing
our methods anymore, either.
敵がその気なら　こちらも鬼札を切ろう
If the enemy wants to play their
trump card, we'll do the same.
Early next morning
また作戦書かね
Another strategy proposal?
Ability:
Little Women
Guild Apprentice
Louisa A.
I, um... Yes.
あの　えっと…
はい
その大長編はどうにかならんのか
Did you have to write an epic novel?
えっと　す…すみません　で…出直します
Umm...
I'm sorry.
I'll redo it.
I'll read it along the way.
移動中に読む　次の作戦エリアは
Where's our next mission site?
I-It's too dangerous.
き…危険です
The cruise ship just fell.
拠点の客船が落ちた今
I'd like you to stay put
inside, Lord Francis.
フランシス様には屋内で大人しくしていただかないと
俺がいる場所がギルドの拠点だ
The Guild's site is wherever I am.
違うか
Is it not?
Hello, young lad.
おや　童
一人かえ
Are you here alone?
何故ここに
Why are you here?
I made a deal with Dazai.
わっちは太宰と取引をしたのじゃ
行方不明の鏡花を救うなら　それを大人しくここで待つ　との
If he is to find and save Kyouka,
I will stay patiently here.
Don't you want to be with Dazai?
童はよいのか　太宰の傍に居らんでも
太宰さんは…
Dazai-san went to negotiate
with a government agent.
政府の代理人との交渉に向かった
何年ぶりですかね　太宰君
How long has it been, Dazai-kun?
I was surprised when I received your call.
連絡を貰った時は驚きましたよ
Hey, Ango.
やあ　安吾　元気そうじゃないか
You're looking well.
Glad you came, Ango.
よく来たね　安吾
Why did you think I'd have forgiven you?
どうして思ったんだい　私が君をもう許していると
Just kidding.
なんてね　どうせこれも弾を抜いてあるのだろう
I bet you left this thing unloaded.
ご用件は
What do you want?
I see.
なるほどの
The Gifted Special Operations Division
異能特務課と云えば　国内最高峰の秘密異能力組織じゃ
is the most powerful secret gifted
organization in the nation.
Get them on your side, and they'll be sure
to become the Agency's greatest weapon.
味方とすれば　探偵社最大の切り札となるじゃろうな
Then Kyouka-chan can come
back to the Agency soon.
そうすれば　遠からず鏡花ちゃんも探偵社に戻ってこられる
I wonder.
どうかの
Say, young boy, do you truly believe
that a young girl of fourteen can,
のう　童
幾月かばかり稽古を受けただけの十四の娘が
三十五人も殺しおおせると　本気で思うのか
with just a few months of training,
kill thirty-five people?
It's her gift.
才能じゃよ
才能が鏡花の魂に黒く絡みついている以上
So long as her gift is bound to her soul,
she'll never escape the darkness.
あの子は闇から抜け出せぬ
Just as I never was able to.
嘗てのわっちと同じようにの
Boy,
童
鏡花を頼む
please take care of Kyouka.
異能力犯罪組織を取り締まるのが特務課のお役でしょう
Isn't it the Special Operations Division's
job to crack down on gifted crime groups?
職務怠慢はよくないな
You shouldn't neglect your duties.
We're aware of the Guild's
activities as well.
ギルドの行動は我々も把握しています
So you knew about it,
and let them off the hook?
知ってて放置したってことかな
They applied pressure on diplomats
連中は外交筋から圧力をかけ
構成員に外交官同等の権限を賦与させました
to grant their members the
same immunities as them.
もはや彼らは法の外の存在
They're above the law.
Law enforcement can't even take
the Guild into custody anymore.
法執行機関はギルドを勾留すらできません
太宰君　逃げてください　今すぐ
Dazai-kun, please, escape.
Immediately.
そして伝えてください
And tell your subordinates that
their lives are in danger.
安吾…
あなたの部下に危険が迫っていま…
Dazai-san's taking a while.
太宰さん　遅いな
待たせたかな
Did I keep you waiting?
What a predictable reaction.
在り来たりの反応だ　つまらん
Boring.
なんて強い力だ　戦闘系の異能力者か
He's too strong.
Does he have combat abilities?
でもこいつを倒せば　戦争は終わりだ
But if I can take him down, the war is over!
今の蹴りはいいな
That was a nice kick.
It was worth at least ten thousand bucks.
一万ドル程度の価値はある
But...
だが
The bounty we've placed on you is seven billion.
我々が君に懸けた懸賞金は七十億
その程度では買えんな
I can't buy you for that much.
But don't get bummed out.
だが　落ち込むことはない
You're valuable for other reasons.
君の価値は別にある
Now, come with me.
さあ　一緒に来てもらおう
これじゃ前と同じだ
It's the same thing all over again.
僕は　また…
Not again.
Wait.
待って
Kyouka.
鏡花…ちゃん
Episode 20
Though the Mind
May be Wrong
So then...
ついにギルドは横浜の街が壊滅するかもしれない恐ろしい作戦を発動させる
昔　僕が読んだ古い本に書いてあった
「私は自分のした事に就いて後悔したことはなかった」
「しなかった事に就いてのみ　何時も後悔を感じていた」
次回　文豪ストレイドッグス　第二十話
頭は間違うことがあっても
今度こそ　必ず僕がみんなを守る